Yannick Le Guennec



FULL-STACK
JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER

- wiseduckdev@gmail.com
- https://wiseduckdev.com
- **P** French and Canadian



Yannick Le Guennec

FULL-STACK JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER

■ wiseduckdev@gmail.com

https://wiseduckdev.com

9 French and Canadian

Summary

Full-Stack JavaScript Developer with 2 years of hands-on experience building web and Al-powered systems using React, Next.js, Node.js, and automation tools. After 17 years managing restaurant operations, I transitioned into tech with a focus on creativity, innovation, agile teamwork, problemsolving, and business development.

Since March 2024, I've delivered multiple freelance projects and led bold personal initiatives, from an autonomous Al-powered media pipeline (X & Substack) to a platform hosting 800+ custom GPTs for web, mobile, Al, blockchain, and game developers. I also apply my background in business strategy, acquired at HEC Montreal, to support startups with business models, marketing, and growth strategies.

I'm now seeking a full-time remote role where I can keep pushing boundaries and growing fast. More at wiseduckdev.com

Technical skills

Programming Languages

JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, SQL, YAML, Shell

Frontend Development

HTML5, CSS3/SASS, Bootstrap, Mantine UI, React, Redux, Next.js, WordPress, Vitest, Formik, Yup

Backend Development

Node.js, Express.js, REST APIs, Swagger, Postman, Dotenv, Nodemailer

Database & ORM

PostgreSQL, pgAdmin, SQL, Sqitch, Faker, Sequelize, Prisma

DevOps & Deployment

Docker, Git, GitHub, YAML, Railway, Vercel, AWS, Linux (Ubuntu), HashiCorp Vault

Al & Automation

Open AI, Perplexity, xAI, Anthropic, Midjourney, Make, Selenium, BeautifulSoup4, Requests, undetected_chromedriver, webdriver_manager, PyVirtualDisplay

APIs & Integrations

Open AI API, xAI API, Perplexity API, X API, Google API (Docs, Sheets, Drive, Gmail), Nodemailer, Tweepy, UA-Parser-JS, google-api-python-client, google-auth, google-auth-oauthlib, AWS SDK

Data Handling & Analysis

Pandas, Numpy, Python-dateutil, pytz, tzdata

Analytics & Monitoring

Google Console, Google Analytics

Cybersecurity

HashiCorp Vault, Oauth2 concepts, Stem, Node Vault

Design & Prototyping

Figma, Canva, Photoshop

Notable Libraries

Axios, date-fns, uuid, xml2js, diff-match-patch, csv-parse, Sharp, next-pwa, meilisearch

Professional experience

Independent Full-Stack Developer

Wise Duck Dev · Remote · March 2024 - Present

- Co-led the development of **Family Flow**, a Reactbased family task manager, in collaboration with a fellow developer. Acted as Product Manager, Scrum Master, and Lead Front-End Developer. Built with TypeScript, Mantine UI, and Vitest; deployed via Railway for users.
- Designed and developed the **Wise Duck Dev GPTs Platform** (V1 & V2), a productivity toolset of
 800+ custom GPTs for web, mobile, AI, blockchain,
 and game developers. Led as Product Manager
 and Full-Stack Developer using Next.js, TypeScript,
 CSS/SASS, OpenAI API, Midjourney, Photoshop,
 Figma, and Make. Paused V3 in anticipation of AGI
 advancements.
- Engineered the **Evidence Media Project**, an Al-powered automated pipeline that finds, curates, and publishes independent news in real time to X and Substack. Developed an end-to-end pipeline with Python, OpenAl API, xAl API, Perplexity API, Tweepy, HashiCorp Vault, and GitHub Actions, publishing real-time content to X and Substack.
- Researched fine-tuning strategies for LLMs on Hugging Face. Built custom datasets using Python, Linux, and Selenium to automate scraping and preprocessing for domain-specific model optimization.
- Delivered freelance projects such as «Jean The Writer» which refers to a custom Al-powered manuscript correction tool using Node.js, TypeScript, OpenAl API, Google Docs API, and diff-match-patch. Enabled automated correction and editorial feedback for manuscripts up to 600 pages.

• Completed additional freelance work in entrepreneurship support: business model design, business plan drafting, marketing strategy creation, and business development consulting, leveraging training from HEC Montréal (Entrepreneurship & Business Creation).

Restaurant Manager

Various Establishments · 2005 – 2022

- Mastered project management and operational efficiency in fast-paced settings, akin to agile web development environments.
- Excelled in problem-solving with a focus on clear, effective communication, mirroring the collaborative nature of tech teams.
- Cultivated a team-oriented environment, fostering innovation and continuous learning, essential in modern tech companies.
- Developed keen insights into client needs, aligning with user experience design principles in tech.
- Demonstrated adaptability and resilience, key for thriving in the dynamic and evolving field of web and mobile development.

Soft skills

- Creativity & Innovation
- Adaptability, Teamwork & Leadership
- Communication, Problem-Solving
- Continuous Learning
- Remote Collaboration

Education

Certificate in web and mobile development full-stack JavaScript - specialized in React

2023-2024

O'Clock, France

Certificate in Entrepreneurship

2020-2021

Finished First of Promotion HEC Montreal, Canada

BSc (Hons) in Gemmology

2016-2020

Finished First Mark
Birmingham City University, England

Certificates

Open Classroom

Development (19):

- · See how algorithms work
- · Understand the Web
- · Learn how to use the line of command in a terminal
- · Create a web site model with Figma
- Create your web site with HTML5 and CSS3
- · Learn how to program with JavaScript
- Introduction to jQuery
- · Get started with TypeScript
- · Manage code with Git and Git Hub
- Become an expert in Git and Git Hub
- Simplify your CSS with SASS
- Create responsive website with Bootstrap 5
- · Get started with React
- Create a complete React app
- Organize your app with Redux logic
- · Get started with REST API
- · Adopt REST APIs for your web projects
- Create your first Web Site with WordPress 6
- Optimize your site's referencing (SEO)

by improving its technical performance

Open Classroom

Blockchain (1):

· Understand Bitcoin and the Blockchain

Systems and Networks (2):

- Optimize your deployment by creating container with Docker
- · Get started with Linux

Cyber Security (2):

- · Secure your data with cryptography
- · Secure your applications

Design (3):

- UX Design : Discover the fundamentals
- Manage a design project with multiples methods of UX mapping
- Make the UX approach your own in practice

Marketing & Communication (1):

 Optimize your site's referencing (SEO) by improving its technical performance

Udemy

ChatGPT Complete Guide:

Learn Midjourney, ChatGPT 4 & more

· Next.js : Complete Course

SLN Academy

Automated ChatGPT

National Agency for Information Systems Security (Anssi)

· SecNum Academy Certificate

Domestika

- Introduction to Adobe Photoshop
- · Digital Collage in Photoshop:

Composition and Visual Effects

Make (Automation)

- · Make Foundation Certificate
- · Make Basics Certificate
- · Make Intermediate Certificate
- · Make Advanced #1 Data stores and data structures
- Make Advanced #2 API calls with HTTP modules